<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Smart Patients &#187; self-efficacy</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/tag/self-efficacy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 02:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The new patient revolution is among us&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/the-new-patient-revolution/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/the-new-patient-revolution/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 23:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-efficacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the network effect]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=87</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So says physician Emma Hill in her piece called “Smart patients” in the current issue of Lancet Oncology. (Free registration required to see the full text.) Emma asked us if she could join Smart Patients to study how cancer patients are using the Smart Patients online community. We are daily witnesses to insightful and moving [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">So says physician Emma Hill in her piece called <a href="http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanonc/article/PIIS1470-2045(14)70044-0/fulltext">“Smart patients” in the current issue of Lancet Oncology</a>. (Free registration required to see the full text.) Emma asked us if she could join Smart Patients to study how cancer patients are using the Smart Patients online community.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We are daily witnesses to insightful and moving conversations between patients and caregivers as they help each other learn about their disease and put it into the context of their own experience. Emma’s reaction: “It is incredible to see how a patient recently diagnosed with a very rare cancer can, the same day, communicate with someone else with the same disease.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">The Smart Patients team has another big goal, in addition to helping patients and caregivers learn from each other. We also want to help them teach the physicians and researchers charged with taking better care of them. The Lancet piece is perhaps a bit bolder:</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr">“The new patient revolution is among us. We, the doctors, might think we are the source of all knowledge, but the age-old model of consulting with your family and friends is now global, with a growing membership to share advice. It is not a replacement doctor, far from it, and the moderators are on hand to guide members. It is a reminder that patients are taking power of their disease, and are educating each other through improved international communication. It should humbly remind us that every patient is an expert in their own chosen field, namely themselves and their own life.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;">It seems there’s something in the air, at least that being breathed by our friends in the UK &#8212; this week BMJ also published a piece called “<a href="http://www.bmj.com/content/348/bmj.g1209">Towards the patient revolution</a>”.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/patients-in-the-air.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-90" alt="patients-in-the-air" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/patients-in-the-air.png" width="771" height="406" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;">In their own efforts to partner with patients, BMJ is considering asking authors of research articles to explain how they involved patients in the design of their study. Tyranny of the commons? No, more like tapping into the most underutilized resource in health care.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;">It’s an exciting privilege for us to be part of the transition from patients as passive recipients of care and passive participants in clinical trials, to patients as true collaborators.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/the-new-patient-revolution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I am the patient and I need to be heard</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/i-need-to-be-heard/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/i-need-to-be-heard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 22:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Network Effect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-efficacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-efficacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the network effect]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=58</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A beautiful thing happened yesterday. A young woman posted a short video from her hospital room: We hear her saying: respect me. There’s a lot to say about how doctors, patients, and caregivers communicate with each other. Here we just want to share a story about the impact this video has already had. Within hours [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A beautiful thing happened yesterday. A young woman posted a short video from her hospital room:</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/BqFfRiyW07I?start=80" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="color: #141412; line-height: 1.5;">We hear her saying: respect me. There’s a lot to say about how doctors, patients, and caregivers communicate with each other. Here we just want to share a story about the impact this video has already had. Within hours of it being posted, a physician in Maine named </span><a style="line-height: 1.5;" href="http://petereliasmd.com">Peter Elias</a><span style="color: #141412; line-height: 1.5;"> saw the video and showed it to a teenage boy in his office who was recently hospitalized and felt more like a piece of furniture than a patient.</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">The boy was quiet for a bit and then said, &#8220;She get&#8217;s it.&#8221; The next time he’s admitted, he plans to have this video queued up on his iPad. &#8220;If they want to examine me or draw blood, they&#8217;re gonna have to watch this first.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr">The way in which we’re connected today means this young woman has just empowered this young man in a way that perhaps no one else could have. Thank you, Peter, for helping make this happen, for sharing this story with us, and for getting the family’s permission for us to comment on it here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/i-need-to-be-heard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
