<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Smart Patients &#187; Roni Zeiger</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/author/roni/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 02:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Thank you and happy new year</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/thank-you-to-the-community/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/thank-you-to-the-community/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 02:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=282</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As we welcome 2015, we’d like thank the broader community that has helped us build useful and supportive communities on Smart Patients. A few of our newest communities are: Acinic Cell Carcinoma Amyloidosis Cystic Fibrosis Graft Versus Host Disease Inflammatory Bowel Disease Leiomyosarcoma Ocular Melanoma Sarcoma Transverse Myelitis So many of you &#8212; whether listed above or not [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we welcome 2015, we’d like thank the broader community that has helped us build useful and supportive communities on Smart Patients.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/thank-you-from-drone.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-283" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/thank-you-from-drone.jpg" alt="thank-you-from-drone" width="2145" height="1199" /></a></p>
<p>A few of our newest communities are:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/acinic-cell-carcinoma">Acinic Cell Carcinoma</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/amyloidosis">Amyloidosis</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/cystic-fibrosis">Cystic Fibrosis</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/gvhd">Graft Versus Host Disease</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/ibd">Inflammatory Bowel Disease</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/leiomyosarcoma">Leiomyosarcoma</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/ocular-melanoma">Ocular Melanoma</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/sarcoma">Sarcoma</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/transverse-myelitis">Transverse Myelitis</a></p>
<p>So many of you &#8212; whether listed above or not &#8212; inspire us everyday and we can&#8217;t wait to learn from your stories this year.</p>
<p>Happy New Year from Roni, Gilles, Robin, Kevin, Allen and Kathryn</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/thank-you-to-the-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vive la difference</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/vive-la-difference/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/vive-la-difference/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=268</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week I (Roni) had the privilege of talking about Smart Patients in Paris, at the Differential Medicine conference. While we expected to see a more conservative approach to medicine, the emerging role of patient as collaborator is clear in Europe too. Perhaps most things sound better in a French accent, but the innovative energy [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week I (Roni) had the privilege of talking about Smart Patients in Paris, at the <a href="http://www.differentialmedicine.com/">Differential Medicine conference</a>. While we expected to see a more conservative approach to medicine, the emerging role of patient as collaborator is clear in Europe too. Perhaps most things sound better in a French accent, but the innovative energy at this conference is the real deal. We talked about the difference between medicine as viewed from inside the hospital or doctor&#8217;s office and what is experienced by patients in the real world.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/shit-myself-in-church.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-269 aligncenter" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/shit-myself-in-church.jpg" alt="shit myself in church" width="495" height="352" /></a></p>
<p><span id="more-268"></span>Patients and caregivers in every country experience things that only they understand. It&#8217;s not always as messy as in the story above, but it&#8217;s this real world context we need to learn more about, understand better, and design solutions for. Health happens in the community and healthcare must happen there too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/vive-la-difference/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data are shadows of stories</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/data-are-shadows-of-stories/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/data-are-shadows-of-stories/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 22:22:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=256</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, I (Roni Zeiger) had the privilege of speaking at RWJF&#8217;s #Data4Health conference in San Francisco. Here I&#8217;ll share a written version of my brief talk and my two slides. I love data. In some contexts, that might sound like a confession. Obviously not here. I grew up loving math, then science. I decided the most interesting secrets [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Today, I (Roni Zeiger) had the privilege of speaking at <a href="http://www.rwjf.org/en/blogs/culture-of-health/2014/11/data4health_livefr.html">RWJF&#8217;s #Data4Health conference</a> in San Francisco. Here I&#8217;ll share a written version of my brief talk and my two slides.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I love data. In some contexts, that might sound like a confession. Obviously not here. </span>I grew up loving math, then science. I decided the most interesting secrets were probably hidden in biology, in particular molecular biology.</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I worked in labs in college, learned how to splice DNA, to make antibodies that were part mouse and part human. </span>It was awesome. It was also a little lonely. The lab was a place where I was looking down more than looking up.</p>
<p class="p1">I then discovered medicine, and found a place where I could do science and stories at the same time. Data and humanity&#8230; but oh man, the data!</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">My Palm Pilot was always with me, and I learned how to write computer programs. </span>You see, the medical center was producing so much data, we just needed better tools to analyze it. I also ended up getting a degree in medical informatics and cemented my identity.</p>
<p class="p1">I still saw patients, something about that kept me grounded, especially when I went to work at Google.</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/brid-connect-a-dot.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-258" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/brid-connect-a-dot.jpg" alt="brid-connect-a-dot" width="3305" height="2311" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">Google&#8230; holy cow, best data ever. I analyzed all the health questions people across the globe were putting into the Google search box. Symptoms, diagnoses. Drugs, supplements. Results of a scan. Good news. Bad news.</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">And I started seeing that those searches represent people. D</span>ata are tiny shadows, projections of rich complex stories.</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Sometimes you can connect the dots, see how a series of searches reveals a new life, or tragedy, hope or fear. </span>And there is SO much more <em>in between</em> those data points.</p>
<p class="p1">Even a child, perhaps especially a child, can show us that. (In this case, one of my children.)</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/bird-colored.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-260" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/bird-colored.jpg" alt="bird-colored" width="3018" height="2133" /></a></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">To be clear: we need more data, and we need better access to data. </span><em>And</em> we need the stories that bring them to life, that give them color and context.</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The data may hold the answers, but stories tell us which questions to ask and stories tell us why the answers matter.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/data-are-shadows-of-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sarcoma research in the last 20 years</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/sarcoma-research-in-the-last-20-years/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/sarcoma-research-in-the-last-20-years/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 01:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=228</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have a look at the graph above representing the evolution of sarcoma trials during the last 20 years. 1995 was significant. We were building the first ACOR online communities and the rapid growth in the number of clinical trials accepting sarcoma patients had begun. However, as you can see, relatively few of the phase 1 [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/sarcoma-trials-graphic.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-229" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/sarcoma-trials-graphic.png" alt="sarcoma trials graphic" width="683" height="464" /></a></p>
<p>Have a look at the graph above representing the evolution of sarcoma trials during the last 20 years. 1995 was significant. We were building the first ACOR online communities and the rapid growth in the number of clinical trials accepting sarcoma patients had begun. However, as you can see, relatively few of the phase 1 and phase 2 trials were followed by phase 3 trials, which are the ones that lead to approval of new drugs.</p>
<p><span id="more-228"></span></p>
<p>Cancer patients suffering from most solid tumors today have many more treatment options than they had 15 years ago, thanks to new targeted therapies and a growing number of trials for various immunotherapies. Unfortunately, that is not the reality for patients with many types of sarcoma. While we see significant activity testing <a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/pathways/pd-1">anti-PD-1 and anti-PD-L1</a> therapies for many cancers, there are few such trials for sarcoma. A more promising observation is the increase in trials for targeted therapies which are accepting sarcoma patients (light blue bars above).</p>
<p>In 1993, <a href="https://www.ctos.org/AboutCTOS/">a wealthy sarcoma patient invited</a> a group of physicians and sarcomas thought leaders to a meeting, contending that these experts were clinical and scientific experts, but were terrible at communicating with each other. Hence was born an international, multidisciplinary, and ongoing sarcoma dialog known as CTOS (the Connective Tissue Oncology Society). This was an inflection point in the history of sarcoma research. CTOS has cultivated cooperation across many sarcoma advocacy organizations</p>
<p>While sarcoma research overall has grown significantly, funding and advances in the treatment of the many less common sarcomas remains low. The graph below shows how the outcome of this research shrinks as we slice the pie to include more rare subtypes of sarcoma, which still affect many people.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Pubmed_Abstracts_Sarcoma_1994_2013-1.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-230" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Pubmed_Abstracts_Sarcoma_1994_2013-1.png" alt="Pubmed_Abstracts_Sarcoma_1994_2013 (1)" width="1812" height="976" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We hope that the near future brings more progress to patients and families of this important group of rare cancers. For those who might want to participate in a sarcoma trial, we&#8217;ve put together this <a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/sarcoma/trials">resource of open sarcoma trials</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/sarcoma-research-in-the-last-20-years/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Online communities for sarcoma</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/online-communities-for-sarcoma/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/online-communities-for-sarcoma/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 21:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=222</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The end of 2014 is turning out to be a period of intense transition in the world of sarcoma online communities. In the same week that ACOR announced it will transition its sarcoma community to Smart Patients, the Liddy Shriver Sarcoma Initiative announced it will close its TeamSarcoma Facebook community. This transitional period has made [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The end of 2014 is turning out to be a period of intense transition in the world of sarcoma online communities. In the same week that ACOR announced it will transition its sarcoma community to <a href="https://smartpatients.com/sarcoma">Smart Patients</a>, the <a href="http://sarcomahelp.org/">Liddy Shriver Sarcoma Initiative</a> announced it will close its TeamSarcoma Facebook community. This transitional period has made me (Gilles Frydman) reflect on what has happened in the world of online support for sarcoma patients and caregivers since the mid-90s.<br />
<span id="more-222"></span><br />
In 1997, a little over a year after I <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/onconurse/news/activist_gilles.html">started ACOR</a> (Association of Cancer Online Resources), we created a group of online communities for sarcoma patients and caregivers. In just a few months, each of these communities grew larger than we expected they’d be after even a few years. At the time, the idea of creating online communities for rare diseases was far from accepted by most healthcare professionals. They warned us of the grave dangers associated with unmoderated, online patient communities. The <a href="http://adc.bmj.com/content/95/8/580.full.pdf">fears expressed</a> by the “experts” were many. The communities would:</p>
<ul>
<li>become a source of constant misinformation since only experts could understand science,</li>
<li>force people to make bad decisions and put them in opposition to their doctors who knew best,</li>
<li>create an army of patients bringing reams of irrelevant printouts to each medical encounter.</li>
</ul>
<p>These fears turned out to be largely unjustified. Countless patients and caregivers have credited online communities for providing information that has saved lives and improved quality of life.</p>
<p>Most of these ACOR communities are still active today, though they have long since stopped growing as new patients and caregivers now expect the ease of use that comes with Facebook. In 2005, at the height of ACOR’s golden age, the various ACOR sarcoma communities had between 300 and 1,200 members each. And each was known as the place to come for high quality information. That last part remains true today.</p>
<p>In 2003, Bev and Bruce Shriver created the Liddy Shriver Sarcoma Initiative which grew into a major funder of sarcoma research and provider of high quality information about all types of sarcoma. As Facebook experienced its explosive growth, the Liddy Shriver Sarcoma Initiative built its own community there. Today that community has 5,000 members. Many more granular sarcoma communities, such as the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/101899709845272/">Angiosarcoma community</a> created by Lauren Ryan, have since grown in Facebook. Remarkably, despite this explosion of online resources, we still regularly receive requests for help from patients with a rare type or subtype of sarcoma. These people often feel they have inadequate support from the medical community and turn to their peers for information that feels like hunting for a needle in a haystack. In fact, data shows that, in the last 20 years, sarcoma research has increased less than research for other types of cancer.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/PubMed_Abstracts_Sarcoma_1994_2013.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-223" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/PubMed_Abstracts_Sarcoma_1994_2013.png" alt="PubMed_Abstracts_Sarcoma_1994_2013" width="1888" height="896" /></a></p>
<p>Historically, sarcoma patients have had active and supportive communities where they can expect high quality information for the many issues associated with rare and complex diseases. As such communities close or cease to grow, I believe that Smart Patients can be the perfect new home that these patients deserve.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/online-communities-for-sarcoma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medical professionals can now &#8220;Learn from Smart Patients&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/learn-from-smart-patients/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/learn-from-smart-patients/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 16:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=211</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve had an increasing number of doctors and other clinicians asking if they can join Smart Patients to learn from what patients are talking about. While many members welcome this, others tell us they want to keep the community as a space for just patients and caregivers. At the same time, they strongly support the idea of the healthcare [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve had an increasing number of doctors and other clinicians asking if they can join Smart Patients to learn from what patients are talking about. While many members welcome this, others tell us they want to keep the community as a space for just patients and caregivers. At the same time, they strongly support the idea of the healthcare system learning from them.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-218" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/smart-patients-learn-logo.png" alt="smart-patients-learn-logo" width="350" height="66" /></p>
<p>So we&#8217;re launching <a href="https://learn.smartpatients.com/">Learn from Smart Patients</a>, a new website and a new program where we are working with medical centers and training programs, to create learning materials for them based on conversations in Smart Patients. Curated conversations are de-identified and used with patient permission.<br />
<span id="more-211"></span><br />
Our first partners are <a href="http://nursing.gwu.edu">George Washington University School of Nursing</a>, <a href="http://www.ahn.org">Allegheny Health Network</a>, and <a href="http://www.cincinnatichildrens.org">Cincinnati Children’s Hospital</a>.</p>
<p>The George Washington University School of Nursing is piloting the service with Nurse Practitioner students studying the role of caregivers. We&#8217;re working closely with Dr. Sandra Davis, Assistant Professor and Director of the University’s Adult-Gerontology Nurse Practitioner Program, who says: “Caregivers are at risk for becoming ill themselves and often suffer physical, emotional, psychological and financial burdens. It is important that primary care providers are able to identify caregivers, assess for caregiver stressors and provide appropriate resources for support.”</p>
<p>Physicians at Allegheny Health Network (AHN) will use the new service to better understand the needs of cancer patients. Our collaborator Barry Bittman, MD, Chief Population Health Officer and Senior Vice President at AHN, says: “The value of more fully understanding the needs of our patients must not be underestimated. Learn from Smart Patients presents an extraordinary opportunity to improve the quality of healthcare delivery by recognizing the concerns and insights shared by our patients and families who are facing often overwhelming healthcare challenges. I personally believe this is a highly valuable patient-centric tool that can assist us in optimizing Triple Aim outcomes.” (We&#8217;re as excited as he is!)</p>
<p>Last and certainly not least, we&#8217;re also launching this service with Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center (CCHMC), where clinicians who care for patients and families affected by cystic fibrosis are reviewing and discussing issues that arise in the Smart Patients cystic fibrosis community. Erin Moore, Family Partner at CCHMC, says: “By having a better understanding of the day to day challenges that patients and families face, clinicians can collaborate with patients more effectively and provide higher quality care.”</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s our goal here, that by learning more about the issues that patients and families deal with between visits, clinicians can more effectively collaborate with patients and provide higher quality care. If you&#8217;d like to collaborate with us on this, <a href="https://learn.smartpatients.com/contact">let us know</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/learn-from-smart-patients/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cancer patients say: let&#8217;s move science faster</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/cancer-patients-say-lets-move-science-faster/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/cancer-patients-say-lets-move-science-faster/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 18:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=207</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In a paper published a few days ago, we shared along with collaborators at Merck that 63 out of 64 cancer patients said they would share their genetic testing results with a pharmaceutical company if the company paid for the testing. Today, scientific progress in oncology is limited in part by the high cost of developing &#8220;companion [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a <a href="http://www.ajmc.com/publications/evidence-based-oncology/2014/September-2014/Patient-Contributed-Tumor-Genetics-Data-A-Pathway-to-Better-Drug-Development">paper published a few days ago</a>, we shared along with collaborators at Merck that 63 out of 64 cancer patients said they would share their genetic testing results with a pharmaceutical company if the company paid for the testing.<br />
<span id="more-207"></span><br />
Today, scientific progress in oncology is limited in part by the high cost of developing &#8220;companion diagnostics&#8221; for each new drug, to be able to test a patient and see if their mutation(s) are a match for the drug. In this paper, researchers at Merck show that from pharma&#8217;s perspective it would be cost-effective to pay for all cancer patients to get next-generation sequencing instead of trying to develop companion diagnostics for every drug, especially since most drugs won&#8217;t make it to market. That is, instead of creating a specific test for each drug, pay for all appropriate patients to get a broader test that can identify all (currently known) mutations and thus which of many drugs are a potential match.</p>
<p>While important privacy issues would need to be worked through, this survey of cancer patients in our community suggests patients are willing to share such sensitive data in order to get testing which they see as critical to choosing their future treatments.</p>
<p>We should note that patients don&#8217;t only want to give researchers a copy of their data &#8212; they want a copy for themselves. What might patients teach us if they were armed with such data?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/cancer-patients-say-lets-move-science-faster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The secret to innovation</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/the-secret-to-innovation/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/the-secret-to-innovation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 23:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=199</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We don&#8217;t actually know the secret of innovation, but we suspect this is part of it: We work in an industrial garage that&#8217;s been converted into a photography studio. When photographer Chris does shoots in the studio, we get unexpected inspiration. Here Ballet San Jose dances while we try to pay attention to the to-do list on the bathroom door. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We don&#8217;t actually know the secret of innovation, but we suspect this is part of it:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ballerinas-sm.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-201" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/ballerinas-sm.jpg" alt="ballerinas-sm" width="7202" height="4282" /></a></p>
<p>We work in an industrial garage that&#8217;s been converted into a photography studio. When photographer Chris does shoots in the studio, we get unexpected inspiration. Here <a href="http://www.balletsj.org/">Ballet San Jose</a> dances while we try to pay attention to the to-do list on the bathroom door. We love our jobs!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/the-secret-to-innovation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding trials for targeted therapies</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/finding-trials-for-targeted-therapies/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/finding-trials-for-targeted-therapies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 23:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=186</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re experimenting with a new feature that makes it easier to find trials of targeted therapies. The live version is here: www.smartpatients.com/lung-cancer/trials. If you click on a cell in the table, you can see the individual trials and click through to its detail page. We built the first version of our trial search engine after patients and caregivers told [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re experimenting with a new feature that makes it easier to find trials of targeted therapies.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/lung-cancer/trials"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-187" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/lung-cancer-trial-table.png" alt="lung-cancer-trial-table" width="868" height="486" /></a></p>
<p>The live version is here: <a href="http://www.smartpatients.com/lung-cancer/trials">www.smartpatients.com/lung-cancer/trials</a>. If you click on a cell in the table, you can see the individual trials and click through to its detail page.<br />
<span id="more-186"></span><br />
We built the first version of our <a href="http://www.smartpatients.com/trials">trial search engine</a> after patients and caregivers told us: we want to look for trials AND discuss which ones might be the best fit for us &#8212; it&#8217;s too hard to do that with clinicaltrials.gov. More guidance from the Smart Patients community led to this experiment.</p>
<p>Feedback is of course welcomed about this design as well as the many lung cancer targeted therapy trials we&#8217;re missing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/finding-trials-for-targeted-therapies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Striving for ordinary</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/striving-for-ordinary/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/striving-for-ordinary/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 15:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caregivers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=177</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a guest blog post by Erin Moore, a mother of four young children. Her 4 year old son Drew has cystic fibrosis, a progressive and fatal genetic disease that does not have a cure. She blogs at www.66roses.com. &#8220;Courage is never to let your actions be influenced by your fears.&#8221;  ~Arthur Koestler Last week [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="wp-image-181 alignright" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/erin-moore-photo.jpeg" alt="erin-moore-photo" width="182" height="182" /></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><span style="line-height: 1.5;">This is a guest blog post by Erin Moore, a mother of four young children. Her 4 year old son Drew has cystic fibrosis, a progressive and fatal genetic disease that does not have a cure. She blogs at <a href="http://www.66roses.com">www.66roses.com</a>.</span></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>&#8220;Cou<em>rage is never to let your actions be influenced by your fears.&#8221;  ~Arthur Koestler</em></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="line-height: 1.5;">Last week I was invited to participate in a meeting in NYC with some of the CF centers in the state. I&#8217;ve been traveling more lately than I had ever really intended to as a stay at home mom, sharing our story and journey from awareness to parti</span>cipation, contribution, and finally ownership. I had the great fortune to have lunch with another amazing CF mom, whose children are now in college.</p>
<p><span id="more-177"></span></p>
<p dir="ltr">She spoke about how back in the early 90&#8217;s, right after the CF gene was discovered, she had created scrapbooks for her children to chronicle the cure that was about to be found. She clipped headlines from the NY Times and Wall Street Journal, magazines articles and photographs about the cure that was right around the corner. She shared her intentions to rent out Veterans Stadium in Philadelphia when they finally announced that a cure had been found.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And then, even with all of that hope, blow by devastating blow the realization came that there might not ever be a cure. The novel treatments that they were exploring weren&#8217;t working. The gene therapy that had promised to end this instead ended the life of the first person that it was injected into. The excitement about the discovery of the defective CFTR gene slowly died, as did much of her hope. She ended her scrapbooks and put them away. She&#8217;s still fighting, but it&#8217;s a different fight now.</p>
<p dir="ltr">When I returned home from my two day trip, it was the middle of the night and I was exhausted. As I always do, I went in to the rooms of my sleeping children to kiss them goodnight before going to bed myself. As I pulled up the covers and touched his sweet forehead with my lips, I could taste cystic fibrosis. He was sweating in his Toy Story pajamas, and a little crust of salt had formed around his hairline. In fact as far back as 1857 a passage in the Almanac of Children&#8217;s Songs and Games from Switzerland warned that &#8216;the child will soon die whose forehead tastes salty when kissed&#8217;, an idea that was proven in 1953 when Paul di Sant&#8217;Agnese revealed the increased salt content of sweat in people with cystic fibrosis.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I got into bed and was unable to sleep, having just experienced a moment of real clarity. When I&#8217;m away, speaking at conference about cystic fibrosis, telling people that we don&#8217;t have time to wait, that my patience is not an option, I consider myself all consumed with this disease. But the reality is that these trips, these times away from my home, these are times that I get to live without the disease. I&#8217;m not administering medicines or listening for a slight change in his breathing or cough, fighting with insurance, or remembering to pack enzymes or hand sanitizer. I had considered myself to be completely engrossed in the disease when I&#8217;m willing to leave my family and take time away to share our story with others&#8230; but I was beginning to realize that these trips, subconsciously, were an escape from it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It was a really humbling awareness, and then it hurt because I realized that I wanted to be away from it all the time. Not from him, but from the disease. I&#8217;m happy and energized and hopeful when I&#8217;m advocating. At home, I&#8217;m working all the time, frustrated and annoyed at how little control I have over the path this disease takes. I started to think about how my advocacy is perhaps providing important balance for me, allowing me to be a part of the disease while separate from it. While this is a healthy escape, the way that I wanted to escape again after kissing that salty head made me feel terrible. I love this family more than anything. I strive for ordinary, but the subtleties that make us extraordinary aren&#8217;t invited and add so much complexity. How can something that brings so much joy also bring so much pain?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Balance is important and it comes in many forms. Experiencing these emotions is helping me understand how I can achieve balance. I make it through my days with a humble awareness of shared humanity. While it feels good to run away, ignorance will swallow up the best parts of us. We are all fighting battles and we all need balance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/striving-for-ordinary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
