<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Smart Patients &#187; cross disease learning</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/tag/crossing-disease-boundaries/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 02:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Our first year together</title>
		<link>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/our-first-year-together/</link>
		<comments>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/our-first-year-together/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 22:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roni Zeiger]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross disease learning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/?p=136</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This Saturday marks the one year anniversary of the very first conversation on Smart Patients. We’re humbled by what we’ve started to build with the amazing people in our community. So far we’ve had over a quarter million visits and over a million page views. But much more important are the stories and how they [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This Saturday marks the one year anniversary of the very first conversation on Smart Patients. We’re humbled by what we’ve started to build with the amazing people in our community. So far we’ve had over a quarter million visits and over a million page views. But much more important are the stories and how they provide context for learning together.</p>
<p>&#8220;Together we are more, and more effective, than we are separately,&#8221; a <a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2009/HEALTH/02/26/ep.kossove.tribute.leiomyosarcoma/index.html">wise cancer community member</a> said often.</p>
<p>We’ve had the painful loss of too many community members and we think about them every day. The community has also given us countless smiles and laughs. It’s also been special for us to start working with communities outside of cancer, like fibromuscular dysplasia.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to our second year, we hope and expect to see more learning within AND across communities. This idea of &#8220;cross disease learning&#8221; keeps on coming up and we often see topics that transcend traditional disease boundaries. Perhaps patient communities can teach the rest of the health care system how to break down some of the silos that limit learning.</p>
<p>Each of us on the Smart Patients team is more grateful than we can say to be a part of this journey. Thank you for working together with us to advance medicine, one story at a time.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/team-picture.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-142" alt="team-picture" src="https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/team-picture.png" width="1080" height="515" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.smartpatients.com/blog/our-first-year-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
